[
    {
        "id" : 1,
        "question" : "Which of the following is the telephone based shared Service Centre?",
        "opt1" : "(a) Call centre",
        "opt2" : "(b) ATM",
        "opt3" : "(c) Phone centre",
        "opt4" : "(d) None of these",
        "ans" : "(a) Call centre"

    },
    {
        "id" : 2,
        "question" : "A facility that allows the user to speak into a special device while typing a letter using computer is called ___",
        "opt1" : "(a) Speaker",
        "opt2" : "(b) Dictaphone",
        "opt3" : "(c) Telephone",
        "opt4" : "(d) Cell phone",
        "ans" : "(b) Dictaphone"
    },
    {
        "id" : 3,
        "question" : "BPO may be expanded as ___",
        "opt1" : "(a) Business Process Outsourcing",
        "opt2" : "(b) Business Product Outsourcing",
        "opt3" : "(c) Business Process Outcome",
        "opt4" : "(d) Business Product Outcome",
        "ans" : "(c) Business Process Outcome"
    },
    {
        "id" : 4,
        "question" : "Collection, digitization and processing of data is basic function of ____",
        "opt1" : "(a) Call centre",
        "opt2" : "(b) Data management",
        "opt3" : "(c) E-Governance",
        "opt4" : "(d) Data collection",
        "ans" : "(d) Data management"
    },
    {
        "id" : 5,
        "question" : "Which of the following is an IT enabled service?",
        "opt1" : "(a) Database",
        "opt2" : "(b) Spreadsheet",
        "opt3" : "(c) Word processor",
        "opt4" : "(d) E-Governance",
        "ans" : "(d) E-Governance"
    },
    {
        "id" : 6,
        "question" : "The term used to refer to the checking of outputs of a computers, with the corresponding input documents, is called",
        "opt1" : "(a) Auditing through the computer",
        "opt2" : "(b) Auditing around the computer",
        "opt3" : "(c) Process control",
        "opt4" : "(d) Beta-test",
        "ans" : "(b) Auditing around the computer"
    },
    {
        "id" : 7,
        "question" : "A channel for communicating across a boundary between two or more subsystem  is known as",
        "opt1" : "(a) Data path",
        "opt2" : "(b) Walk through",
        "opt3" : "(c) Act gram",
        "opt4" : "(d) Interface",
        "ans" : "(d) Interface"
    },
    {
        "id" : 8,
        "question" : "A turnkey package includes",
        "opt1" : "(a) Training",
        "opt2" : "(b) Software",
        "opt3" : "(c) Hardware",
        "opt4" : "(d) All of these",
        "ans" : "(d) All of these"
    },
    {
        "id" : 9,
        "question" : "Which of the following is not true of the conversion phase of the development life cycle?",
        "opt1" : "(a) Documentation should be emphasized",
        "opt2" : "(b) The non-machine components of the system should be considered",
        "opt3" : "(c) Steps must be taken to phase out the old system",
        "opt4" : "(d) The user and systems personnel must work closely together",
        "ans" : "(a) Documentation should be emphasized"
    },
    {
        "id" : 10,
        "question" : "In the system concepts, the term organization",
        "opt1" : "(a) Refers to the holism of systems",
        "opt2" : "(b) Means that parts of the computer system depend on one another",
        "opt3" : "(c) Refers to the manner in which each component functions with other components of the system",
        "opt4" : "(d) Implies structure and order",
        "ans" : "(d) Implies structure and order"
    }
   

]
